Finding Aid for Michigan Library Association records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Executive Board, 1891-1981
  - President and Committee Annual Reports, 1948-1951; 1915; 1935 (Box 19)
  - Minutes/Reports
    - (1 v.), 1891-1908 (Box 19)
    - (1 v.), 1909-1913 (Box 19)
    - (1 v.), 1914-1917 (Box 19)
    - (1 v.), 1918-1924 (Box 19)
    - 1951-1959 (Box 19)
    - 1960-1964 (Box 19)
    - 1965-1968 (Box 19)
    - 1969-19-2 (Box 19)
    - 1973-19-,6 (Box 19)
    - 1977-1981 (Box 19)
  - Correspondence, 1909-1982
    - 1909-1911 (Box 19)
    - l917-19i8, 1915 (Box 19)
    - 1925-1928 (Box 19)
    - 1954-1956 (Box 19)
    - 1960 (Box 19)
    - 1961 (Box 19)
    - 1962 (Box 19)
    - 1963 (Box 19)
    - 1964 (Box 19)
    - 1965 (Box 19)
    - 1966 (Box 19)
    - 1967 (Box 19)
    - 1968 (Box 19)
    - 1970 (Box 19)
    - 1971 (Box 20)
    - 1972 January-February (Box 20)
    - 1972 March-April (Box 20)
    - 1972 May (Box 20)
    - 1972 June-December (Box 20)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 20)
    - 1975 (Box 20)
    - 1976 (Box 20)
    - 1977 (Box 20)
    - 1978 (Box 20)
    - 1979 (Box 20)
    - 1980 January-June (Box 20)
    - 1980 July-December (Box 20)
    - 1981 (Box 20)
    - 1982 (Box 20)
  - President and Vice-President Correspondence
    - 1961 (Box 20)
    - 1962 (Box 20)
    - 1963 (Box 20)
    - 1964 (Box 20)
    - 1965 (Box 20)
    - 1966 (Box 20)
    - 1967 (Box 20)
    - 1968 (Box 20)
  - Vice-President, Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 20)
  - Executive Secretary (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - 1959-1961 (Box 21)
      - 1962 (Box 21)
      - 1964 (Box 21)
      - 1965 (Box 21)
      - 1966-1967
        - 1968-1969 (Box 21)
  - Financial
    - Statements and budgets
      - 1954-1955 (Box 21)
      - 1962-1979 (Box 21)
    - Treasurer's Correspondence
      - 1954-1966 (Box 21)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 21)
      - 1974, 1975; 1978 (Box 21)
- ALA Councilor
  - Correspondence, 1964; 1982 (Box 21)
- Divisions, 1926-1982
  - Academic (College)
    - Minutes, 1951-1954; 1957-1960; 1963-1964; 1973; 1975-1976; 1979-1982 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - 1950-1955 (Box 21)
      - 1956-1957 (Box 21)
      - 1960-1964 (Box 21)
      - 1971-1976, 1981-1982 (Box 21)
    - Membership Lists (Box 21)
    - Special Committee on Cooperative Library Service to Extension Students, 1960-1961 (Box 21)
  - Friends of the Library Division
    - Minutes, 1962-1969; 1979-1982 (Box 21)
    - Correspondence
      - 1962-1964 (Box 21)
      - 1965 January-June (Box 21)
      - 1965 July-December (Box 21)
      - 1966 (Box 21)
      - 1967 (Box 22)
      - 1968 (Box 22)
      - 1969 (Box 22)
      - 1971 (Box 22)
      - 1972 (Box 22)
      - 1974-1976, 1980 (Box 22)
    - Newsletter, 1965-1968 (Box 22)
    - Membership Lists, 1964; 1967; 1968 (Box 22)
    - Stuff-collected from various libraries, promotions of Friends group, 3 folders (Box 22)
  - Public Library Division
    - Minutes, 1974-1982 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence, 1972; 1975; 1977; 1980-1982 (Box 22)
    - Membership Lists (Box 22)
  - School Library
    (School and Children's Library Division)
    - Minutes
      - (1 v.), 1935-1950 (Box 22)
      - 1957-1973, 1975-1976 (Box 22)
    - Correspondence
      - 1960-1963 (Box 22)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 22)
      - 1968-1974, 1981-1982 (Box 22)
    - Treasurer's Report, 1951-1968 (Box 22)
    - Membership Lists, 1961; 1963-1967 (Box 22)
    - Publications Committee
      - Correspondence, 1945-1951 (Box 22)
      - General publishers (articles) (Box 22)
      - Michigan Librarian, 1945-1951 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Education Association Journal (Box 22)
      - Library Journal, 1948-1951 (Box 22)
      - Michigan Library News, 1946-1951 (Box 22)
    - Conference on Children's Reading, (1 v.), 1926-1941 (Box 22)
  - Trustee Division
    - Minutes
      - 1959-1969 (Box 23)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 23)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 23)
      - 1978-1982 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence
      - 1959-1962 (Box 23)
      - 1963-1966 (Box 23)
      - 1968-1969, 1976; 1979; 1981 (Box 23)
    - Trustee Citation Awards --, 1960-1970 (Box 23)
    - Manuals and Checklists (Box 23)
    - Newsletter, 1959-1960 (Box 23)
    - Survey of Local and National Trustee Groups, 1963-1964 (Box 23)
    - Membership Lists (Box 23)
    - District Trustee Lists, 1959-1962 (Box 23)
- Sections
  - Adult Education
    - Minutes, 1959-1960; 1963-1964; 1967 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1968 (Box 23)
    - Membership Lists (Box 23)
  - Children Services
    - Minutes
      - 1967-1974 (Box 23)
      - 1975-1977, 1980-1982 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence
      - 1967-1970 (Box 23)
      - 1971 (Box 23)
      - 1972 (Box 23)
      - 1973-1975 (Box 23)
    - Spring Institutes
      - 1952-1958 (Box 23)
      - 1960-1962, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
      - 1967 (Box 23)
      - 1968 (Box 23)
      - 1969 (Box 23)
      - 1970 (Box 23)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 24)
      - 1974-1975 (Box 24)
    - Booklist-1972 (Box 24)
    - Nominations-1971-1972 (Box 24)
    - Visit of Japanese Librarian -- sponsored by CSRT, 1971 (Box 24)
  - Community College
    - Minutes/Correspondence, 1964; 1972; 1976-1977; 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - Cooperative Caucus
    (Systems Roundtable)
    - Minutes, 1968-1975; 1977-1978; 1980-1981 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence
    - 1969, 1973-1974 (Box 24)
    - 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 24)
  - County and Regional
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists, 1961-1967 (Box 24)
  - Hospital and Institutional Libraries
    - Minutes/Reports, 1944-1967 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence
      - 1957, 1962-1964 (Box 24)
      - 1965-1967 (Box 24)
      - 1968 (Box 24)
    - Spring Meetings-1959-1962 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists (Box 24)
  - Junior College
    - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists (Box 24)
  - Junior Members
    - Minutes
      - 1955-1966 (Box 24)
      - 1968-1970 (Box 24)
      - 1974-1975, 1978-1979 (Box 24)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence
      - 1955-1966 (Box 24)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 24)
      - 1970-1973 (Box 24)
      - 1974-1982 (Box 24)
    - Programs, 1956-1963 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists (Box 24)
  - Library Administration
    - Correspondence, 1964-1965; 1967 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists, 1961-1967 (Box 24)
  - Library Development
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Media (Audio-Visual)
    - Annual Reports, 1960-1973 (Box 24)
    - Minutes, 1962-1971 (Box 24)
    - Correspondence, 1964; 1967-1968; 1970-1973 (Box 24)
    - Membership Lists, 1961; 1964; 1966-1969; 1972-1973 (Box 24)
    - Michigan Film Network Proposals, 1964-1971 (Box 24)
    - Nominating Committee, 1961-1963; 1965; 1967; 1971-1973 (Box 24)
    - Film Showings, 1967-1970 (Box 24)
    - Bylaws-changes, 1963-1971 (Box 24)
    - Spring Institutes, 1971; 1973 (Box 24)
  - Reference
    - Minutes, 1962-1966; 1973-1980 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence
      - 1934-1948 (Box 25)
      - 1949-1952 (Box 25)
      - 1953-1961 (Box 25)
      - 1962-1966, 1968 (Box 25)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 25)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 25)
      - 1975-1976 (Box 25)
      - 1977-1979 (Box 25)
      - 1980-1982 (Box 25)
    - Membership Lists, 1961-1964; 1966-1967; 1969 (Box 25)
    - ALA Reference Section-1961 (Box 25)
  - Special Libraries
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970; 1972 (Box 25)
  - Specialized Services Roundtable
    - Correspondence, 1974; 1975 (Box 25)
  - Support Staff
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 25)
  - Technical Services
    - Minutes
      - 1927-1954 (Box 25)
      - 1955-1968 (Box 25)
      - 1969-1977, 1982 (Box 25)
    - Correspondence
      - 1961-1962, 1964-1966 (Box 25)
      - 1968-1977 (Box 25)
  - Cost Accounting Study
    - Minutes, 1962 (Box 25)
    - Membership Lists, 1961-1969 (Box 25)
  - Young Adult (Box 25)
- Activities Committees, 1949-1982
  - Continuing Education
    - Minutes, 1975-1977; 1979-1981 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence, 1971; 1976; 1981 (Box 26)
    - Midwest Conference, 1971 (Box 26)
      (CE segment)
  - Intellectual Freedom Committee
    - Minutes/Reports, 1962-1963; 1965-1966; 1982 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence
      - 1959, 1962-1966 (Box 26)
      - 1971, 1974-1977 (Box 26)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 26)
  - Legislative Committee
    - Minutes
      - 1973-1975, 1962-1964; 1966 (Box 26)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 26)
      - 1979-1981 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence
      - 1960, 1962 (Box 26)
      - 1963 (Box 26)
      - 1964 (Box 26)
      - 1965 (Box 26)
      - 1966-1968, 1971 (Box 26)
      - 1972 (Box 26)
      - 1973 (Box 26)
      - 1974 (Box 26)
      - 1975 (Box 26)
      - 1976, 2 folders (Box 26)
      - 1977 (Box 27)
      - 1978, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - 1979 (Box 27)
      - 1980 (Box 27)
      - 1981 (Box 27)
      - 1982 (Box 27)
    - Newsletters, 1954; 1961-1968 (Box 27)
    - Report, 1971; 1973-1974 (Box 27)
    - Statewide Plan for Library Service, 1960-1964 (Box 27)
    - Alberta Brown, 1965 (Box 27)
      (Special MLA Representative)
    - Tri-State Legislative Workshop, 1966 (Box 27)
    - Findings of Senate Resolution 282, 1972 (Box 27)
      (Library Study Report)
    - Planning Meeting-SB 344, 1972-PA 89, 1977-transcript (Box 27)
    - Revenue Sharing, 1974-1975 (Box 27)
    - PA 277, suit-Friend of Court brief-public employees, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Teleconference, 1981 (Box 27)
    - Letters to Legislators
      (sampled)
      - SB 200-2015, 1981 (Box 27)
      - Budget Cuts, 1980 (Box 27)
      - Budget Cuts, 1973-1974 (Box 27)
  - Public Relations Committee
    - Minutes, 1957-1967; 1971; 1978-1982 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence
      - 1949-1962 (Box 27)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 27)
      - 1971-1972, 1979-1982 (Box 27)
  - Salaries Survey: Personnel Policies, Salary, Staff and Tenure
    - Minutes, 1955-1968; 1980-1982 (Box 28)
    - Correspondence
      - 1955-1964 (Box 28)
      - 1965-1969 (Box 28)
    - Surveys, 1959-1963 (Box 28)
    - Wage and Salary Scales, 1966-1968 (Box 28)
- Operations Committee, 1984-1982
  - Awards
    - Correspondence
      - 1964-1972 (Box 28)
      - 1976-1982 (Box 28)
    - Librarian of the Year
      - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 28)
    - Loletta Fyan Award
      - Correspondence
        - 1963-1965 (Box 28)
        - 1966-1969 (Box 28)
  - Conference
    - Conference Programs
      - 1894-1895, 1897-1902 (Box 28)
      - 1904, 1906-1913 (Box 28)
      - 1915-1929 (Box 28)
      - 1937-1942 (Box 28)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 28)
      - 1948-1969 (Box 28)
    - Conference Statistics (covering years 1891-1964) (Box 28)
    - Summary Financial Statistics, 1959-1963; 1965-1966 (Box 28)
    - Requests for Meetings-sample forms (Box 28)
    - Manual of Procedures (Box 28)
    - "How to Run a Conference" packet (Box 28)
    - Conferences
      - Correspondence
        - 1957 (Box 28)
        - 1958 (Box 28)
        - 1959 (Box 28)
        - 1960 (Box 28)
      - Correspondence
        - 1962 (Box 29)
        - 1963 (Box 29)
        - 1964 (Box 29)
        - 1966 (Box 29)
        - 1967 (Box 29)
        - 1968 (Box 29)
        - 1969 (Box 29)
        - 1970-1971 (Box 29)
        - 1976 (Box 29)
      - Packets
        - 1964 (Box 29)
        - 1965 (Box 29)
        - 1966 (Box 29)
        - 1967 (Box 29)
        - 1968 (Box 29)
      - Photographs (Box 29)
      - Publicity
        - 1965 (Box 29)
        - 1968 (Box 29)
        - 1969 (Box 29)
    - C9orrespondence, 1962-1964; 1966 (Box 29)
  - Headquarters
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 29)
  - History
    - Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 29)
  - Institutes and In-Service Training
    - Minutes, 1940 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence
      - 1940 (Box 29)
      - 1941 (Box 29)
  - Assorted Conference and Institute Programs (Box 29)
  - Membership
    - Annual Report
      - 1951, 1954 (Box 30)
      - 1959-1969 (Box 30)
      - 1975 (Box 30)
    - Minutes, 1954-1961; 1964-1965; 1967-1968; 1972; 1975; 1978-1980; 1982 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence
      - 1947-1962 (Box 30)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 30)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 30)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 30)
      - 1971-1972 (Box 30)
      - 1974-1977, 1980-1981 (Box 30)
    - Honorary Memberships, 1949; 1953 (Box 30)
    - Membership Lists, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
    - Committee Lists, 1956; 1959-1965 (Box 30)
    - Sample Forms and Letters (Box 30)
  - Nomination and Elections
    - Correspondence
      - 1952-1962 (Box 30)
      - 1963-1965 (Box 30)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 30)
      - 1971, 1976; 1980-1981 (Box 30)
  - Planning
    - Minutes/Reports, 1953-1967 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence
      - 1955-1963 (Box 30)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 30)
  - Policy
    - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 30)
  - Professional Affairs
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 30)
  - Publications
    - Minutes/Reports
      - 1958-1959 (Box 30)
      - 1961, 1963-1965 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence, 1957-1966 (Box 30)
    - Michigan Librarian
      - Correspondence
        - 1963-1965 (Box 30)
        - 1978 (Box 30)
        - 1981-1982 (Box 30)
  - Recruitment and Scholarship
    - Minutes/Reports
      - 1947-1948 (Box 30)
      - 1960, 1962-1966; 1969 (Box 30)
    - Correspondence
      - Recruitment, 1955-1960 (Box 30)
      - Scholarship, 1955-1962 (Box 30)
      - 1964-1966 (Box 30)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 30)
    - Constance Bement Memorial Fund
      - Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 31)
    - Inter-Association Library Scholarship Fund
      - Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 31)
    - Flyers, Pamphlets and Materials on Careers and Scholarships (Box 31)
  - Resolution
    - Correspondence, 1955-1961 (Box 31)
- Districts, 1917-1977
  - Roundtables (early name)
    - Minutes/Reports, 1933-1939 (Box 31)
      (scrapbook)
    - Minutes/Reports, 1917; 1920 (Box 31)
      (loose)
  - Meetings (programs), 1951-1952; 1955-1966 (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 31)
  - Manual of Procedures for District Offices (Box 31)
  - Membership Lists
    - 1958 (Box 31)
    - 1959 (Box 31)
    - 1961 (Box 31)
    - 1962 (Box 31)
    - 1963 (Box 31)
    - 1964 (Box 31)
    - 1965 (Box 31)
    - 1966 (Box 31)
    - 1967 (Box 31)
  - District I
    - Correspondence
      - 1964, 1966 (Box 31)
    - Dr. When Chao Chen, 1960-1967 (Box 31)
      (treasurer of MLA, chair of District I)
  - District III
    - Annual Reports, 1939-1965 (Box 31)
    - Annual Meetings programs, 1940-1950; 1952; 1954; 1957; 1959; 1962 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence
      - 1952-1961 (Box 31)
      - 1962-1963 (Box 31)
      - 1964 (Box 31)
      - 1965 (Box 31)
  - District V
    - Minutes /Reports, 1960-1967 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1964 (Box 31)
  - Detroit Suburban Librarians RT
    - Correspondence, 1972-1974; 1977 (Box 31)
- Related Library Groups/Associations, 1954-1976
  - Michigan Association for Media in Education (MAME)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Association of School Librarians
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Council for Better Libraries
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 32)
  - Midwest Federation of Library Associations
    - Conference, 1975 (Box 32)
  - State Board for Libraries
    - Minutes
      - 1954, 1957; 1959-1964; 1966-1968 (Box 32)
      - 1978-1981 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 32)
    - A State Plan, 1960 (Box 32)
  - Other Library Associations (Box 32)
- Workshops/Conferences/Projects, 1965-1981
  - First Governor's Conference on Libraries Packet, 1962 (Box 32)
  - 75th Anniversary Celebration
    - Minutes/Reports, 1964; 1966 (Box 32)
    - Correspondence
      - 1964 (Box 32)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 32)
    - History of MLA, 1966 (Box 32)
      (final chapter)
  - Metropolitan Project
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 32)
  - Regional Conference
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 32)
  - Michigan Council for the Arts
    (grant)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 32)
  - "Marketing of Library Services"
    - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 32)
  - "A Model for Networking"
    - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 32)
    - Final Report (Box 32)
  - Workshops of Projects (Box 32)
- MLA Administrative Materials, 1924-1966
  - Manuals (Box 32)
  - Check Lists for Committee Heads (Box 32)
  - Sample Form Letters (Box 32)
  - Committee Descriptions (Box 32)
  - Committee on Certification
    - Correspondence, 1924-1928 (Box 33)
  - Special Finance Committee
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 33)
  - Joint Committee to Study Library Standards
    - Correspondence, 1958-1959 (Box 33)
  - Special Committee on Library Laws
    - Minutes, 1961 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 33)
  - Public Act 379 Committee
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 33)
  - Joint Committee on School Library Development
    - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 33)
- Miscellaneous
  - State Legislation Penal Fines and Libraries
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 33)
  - Governors Report re: Educational Reform
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 33)
  - School District Public Libraries
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 33)
  - Hamtramck Case
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 33)
  - Service to Shut-ins and Retirees (Box 33)
    (correspondence)
  - Assorted Library Related Materials, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Reel to Reel Tapes (23 reels) (Box 33)
  - Visual Materials
    (3/4" U-Matic video/cassettes except where noted)
    - "So You're Able to Cable" Conference, by Wayne Oakland Library Federation, ?, 1982 (Box 34)
    - How TV Works, 2 videotapes (Box 34)
    - Editing Video Tape; Cameras (Box 34)
    - Equipment Purchase Procedures (Box 34)
    - 20 Steps of Television Production, 3 videotapes (Box 34)
    - "The Future of Michigan Libraries" Teleconference, shortened version, 2 copies (Box 35)
    - "What Price Success," with Ed Howard (Box 35)
    - "Stretching Limited Library Budget," with Dr. Ellen Atima (Box 35)
    - "The Library Trustee's Responsibilities in Maintaining, Fiscally Healthy Library," with Daniel W. Casey (Box 35)
    - MLA public relations shorts (Box 35)
      (16 mm film)
    - Children's Services Round Table Conferences (Box 36)
      (l/2" videotape reels)
      - "Nancy Drew or Not Nancy Drew,", May 2, 1974; 3 videotapes (Box 36)
      - "Sexism in Books," with Jo Jacobs, May 3, 1974; 3 videotapes (Box 36)
      - "De-Sexing the Media," with Lee Jameson, May 9, 1975 (Box 36)
      - Tomie de Paola, May 9, 1975 (Box 36)
    - "Women in Michigan Libraries," Summer, 1976 (Box 36)
      (l/2" videotape reel)
    - "The Trustee's Role in Library Funding," with Casey, Short, and Messing, June 21, 1976 (Box 36)
      (1/2" videotape reel)
    - MLA Conference, 1976
      (1/2" videotape reels)
      - Maya Angelou (Box 36)
      - Dr. Berlo, 2 videotapes (Box 36)
- General MLA, 1966-1989
  The papers received in this accession cover the years 1937-1952 and 1961-1989 with the bulk of the material from 1980-1989. The accession consists of 8 linear feet and is arranged in 3 series.
  The first series, General MLA, consists of papers pertaining to the general programs, operations and finances of the MLA as a complete unit. Series two, Sections, is devoted to different sections within the MLA. This series deals with the various divisions, caucuses, and committees that have an interest in one area of librarianship such as children's services or intellectual freedom. The third series, County Libraries, is a late accession of material from 1937-1952 and deals with rural libraries during and immediately following World War II.
  The material has been arranged alphabetically by topic. If the topic contained more material than one folder it was divided into subtopics and arranged alphabetically and the chronologically when necessary.
  The accession as a whole strongly documents the activities necessary to run such an association. This information can be found in the records dealing with grant proposals, nomination and election of officers, finances, policies and procedures, and planning programs and workshops. These types of material can be found in each series.
  Series I: General MLA
  This series contains information on the general operations of the MLA. The stronger aspects of this series are the records relating to finances, awards, the executive board, membership, organizational structure, conferences, and workshops. The constitution and bylaws are found within the Policies and Procedures Manual.
  - Aaron Court Case, 1982 (Box 37)
  - ALA Councilor, 1983 (Box 37)
  - Annual Meeting, 1984; 1987 (Box 37)
  - Audit, 1984-1987 (Box 37)
  - Awards
    - 1977-1983 (Box 37)
    - 1984-1986 (Box 37)
    - 1987-1989 (Box 37)
  - Benton Harbor Court Case, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Children's Literature Association, undated (Box 37)
  - Conference, 1966; 1981; 1988 (Box 37)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 37)
  - County Law Library Survey, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Editorial Board, 1982-1988 (Box 37)
  - Energy Grant, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Energy Grant Manual, 1980 (Box 37)
  - Executive Board
    - General, 1982-1984 (Box 37)
    - Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 37)
  - Finances, 1970; 1980-1982 (Box 37)
  - Financial Reports, 1973-1983 (Box 37)
  - Form Letters, 1983-1984 (Box 37)
  - Goals and Objectives, 1982-1988 (Box 37)
  - Headquarters and Finance
    - Correspondence and Reports, 1982-1984 (Box 37)
    - Minutes, 1983-1988 (Box 37)
  - Kellogg Foundation, 1976-1977 (Box 37)
  - Leadership Conference, Academy, and Workshop, 1981; 1983; 1988 (Box 37)
  - Legal Information Network, 1981-1983 (Box 37)
  - Legislative Day, 1981 (Box 37)
  - Libraries Celebrate 150!, 1986 (Box 37)
  - Long-Range Plan, 1988 (Box 37)
  - Management Seminar, 1985 (Box 37)
  - Membership (Box 38)
    - General, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
    - Minutes and Reports
      - 1983-1984 (Box 38)
      - 1985-1988 (Box 38)
  - Membership Rosters, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Networking Conference, 1981 (Box 38)
  - Michigan Library Statistics, 1981-1982 (Box 38)
  - Nominations, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Officers and Committee Members, 1980-1988 (Box 38)
  - Organization Structure, 1988-1989 (Box 38)
  - Penal Fines, 1980-1986 (Box 38)
  - Policies and Procedures
    - 1971, 1973; 1983 (Box 38)
    - 1988 (Box 38)
  - President, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Reports, 1984-1988 (Box 38)
  - Resolutions, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
  - Salary Survey, 1981-1984 (Box 38)
  - Single Business Tax Act, 1983 (Box 38)
  - Trustees
    - 1982-1984 (Box 38)
    - 1985-1988 (Box 38)
  - Workshop Approval and Planning, 1977; 1988 (Box 38)
- Sections, 1975-1989
  This series documents the activities of divisions, caucuses and committees within the MLA. This series has been assigned the general name of sections because the titles of these groups sometimes change. Therefore, the titles of division, caucus, and committee have been omitted. This series also includes organizations not directly a part of the MLA, but which support MLA objectives. Examples of these organizations are the Council of Michigan Library Organizations and the Library of Michigan.
  The most strongly documented sections include Children's services, Continuing Education, Educational Foundation, Friends, Intellectual Freedom, Legislative, Michigan Interorganization Council on Continuing Library Education, Public Libraries, and Young Adults. Each of these sections have varying research value.
  - Academic and Research Library, 1982-1984 (Box 38)
  - Bibliographic Instruction, 1978; 1984-1988 (Box 39)
  - Children's Services
    The largest section is Children's Services consisting of approximately one linear foot. The collection strongly documents Spring Institutes, and Summer Reading Programs. This section contains a fairly complete record of minutes spanning the years 1975-1988 that document the issues of the group and how they were addressed.
    - Annual Report, 1983-1986 (Box 39)
    - Conferences, 1984-1988 (Box 39)
    - Correspondence, 1978-1988 (Box 39)
    - Finances, 1978-1985 (Box 39)
    - Goals and Objectives, 1983-1984 (Box 39)
    - History, 1982 (Box 39)
    - Membership Rosters, 1979-1987 (Box 39)
    - Minutes
      - 1975-1979 (Box 39)
      - 1980-1981 (Box 39)